片名：生死时速
[ 小 心 ]
嘿  这儿不能进来
Hey, this area's restricted.
嗨  你好  是他们通知我来的
Hi. Yeah, I know. They called me down here.
让我来检查线路
Some of this wiring got screwed up.
怎么没人通知我  给我看一下单据
Nobody called it down to me. I'm gonna have to see a work order.
好  请稍等
Yeah. Just a second.
看吧
There you are.
你自找的
Nothing personal.
今天就到这儿吧  诸位辛苦了
Well, I guess that wraps it up. Good work, everybody.
马提  我认为你这计划很好
Marty, I couldn't be happier with the way this worked out.
衷心祝贺你
Congratulations.
别关
Hold that.
谢谢你支持
Gee, thanks.
多谢你帮忙  鲍布
Thanks for pushing that, Bob. The light's on,
不过要是指示灯坏了也说不定呢
but you never know, it might be broken.
别胡说
Shut up.
知道吗  亲爱的  今天会上...
Remember, honey...
我的天  鲍布  你按了什么钮?
Jesus. Bob, what button did you push?
这幢楼里其它电梯是不是都停止使用了?
Mr Bagwell, make sure these other elevators remain locked down and empty.
除了维修窗  现在没有任何地方可以进入电梯
There's no doors, no other way in or out, except through access panels, correct?
现在有十三位乘客被困在电梯里  在三十层不到
What we have here are 13 passengers in an express elevator below floor 30.
缆绳被炸断了  案犯向我们提出要三百万元的赎金
Bomb's taken out cables. Bomber wants $3 million or he blows the brakes.
- 给多少时间?  - 就一个小时
- What's our clock? - He gave one hour.
可现在只剩下二十三分钟了
That leaves us 23 minutes exactly.
不能让电梯再坠落下去
Anything to keep this elevator from falling?
底层
The basement.
当局要防止惨剧发生
We'd like to avoid that, Traven.
- 要想办法把人救出来  - 那可是架高速电梯
- We can't unload the passengers? - This is an express elevator.
案犯把炸药安装在启动闸上
The only way in is through access panels. The bomber's wired the hatch,
他随时都可以让电梯坠落
which seats him in the "crazy but not stupid" section.
哈里要求到现场去看一下
Sir, Harry volunteers to examine the device.
- 没错  - 好吧  你们俩一起去
- Yeah, right. - Fine. The two of you check it out.
离电梯最近的维修窗在第三十二层
The nearest access panel's on the 32nd floor in the lobby.
摸清情况  不许擅自行动
I want reports only. We're in a holding pattern.
沃西  比格  你们两个去守住大门
Worthy, Briggs, secure the base area.
其他人  尽快把楼里人疏散出去  快行动
Everyone else, I want you to affirm building evac. Move!
爬楼吧
Looks like we're walkin'.
- 快点  快点  留神脚下  - 二十九
- Hurry, but watch your step! - 29.
到底下大厅  快一点
All the way down to the lobby! Let's go, folks!
三十
30.
三十一
31.
三十二
32.
喂
Hello?
- 快让我们出去  - 喂  喂
- Come on! Get us outta here! - Hello! Hello!
来人  快来人  让我们出去
Help! Please, get us out of here!
来人啊
Please!
来人  让我们出去
Please! Get us out of here!
上面有人吗?  有人吗?  这是怎么了?
Who's up there? Who's up there? What's going on?
女士们  先生们  我们是警察
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the LAPD.
- 谢天谢地  - 你们来干什么?
- Thank God. - What are you doing up there?
这架电梯出了点故障  大家别紧张
There's been an elevator malfunction, so just relax.
快点  快点想想办法
Hey, come on! What are you guys waiting for?
别急  你们很快能出来
We'll have you out of there as soon as possible.
我骗人?
Am I lying?
干嘛派警察来?  警察会修电梯?
How come they sent cops here? Shouldn't they send repair guys?
你怎么想?
What do you think?
- 听你的  你是专家  - 干得很巧妙
- You're the expert. I just work here. - Looks pretty solid.
- 像谁干的?  - 不知道  可准是个老手
- Anyone we know? - I don't recognise the work, but he's a pro.
- 时间不多了  - 真急人
- He's cutting it close. - I don't like it.
急也没用  麦克让等只好等
Well, what's to like? Mac said we hold, so we hold.
临时测试  机场  案犯挟持一名人质朝前跑
All right, pop quiz. The airport. Gunman with one hostage.
眼看要到机舱口
He's using her for cover. He's almost to a plane.
你还在百米之外
You're 100 feet away.
杰克
Jack.
打伤人质
Shoot the hostage.
- 什么?  - 先朝人质开枪
- What? - Take her out of the equation.
把人质打伤再瞄准案犯  就这样
Go for the good wound and he can't get to the plane with her. Clear shot.
真亏你想得出来  朝人质开枪  哼
You're deeply nuts, you know that? "Shoot the hostage. "
有点不对劲  他打算炸电梯
Harry, this is wrong. He's gonna blow it anyway.
- 怎么知道?  - 只是凭直觉
- Why? - I don't know. Gut feeling.
行了  等着麦克下命令  沉住气
Right now Mac outranks your gut, so we sit.
怎么还没有修好?
This is taking way too long.
这电梯重量多少?
How much d'you think that elevator weighs?
杰克  得了
Jack, come on.
我有个主意  也许有点用
Maybe we can do something about those hostages.
想朝人质开枪?
We're not gonna shoot 'em, right?
嗨  去哪儿?  这是怎么了?
Hey, where you going? What's going on?
别走  别离开我们
Don't go! Don't leave us here!
不  我想帮他们摆脱困境
No, we just take them out of the equation.
- 能行吗?  - 可以
- Are you sure it'll hold? - It'll hold.
六分钟
Six minutes.
不能再这么拖下去了  他又不答话
I can't get any more time. He's not talking!
赶快把赎金送过来
I need the goddamn money now.
你说说  哈里  我这是图个什么?
Tell me again, Harry. Why did I take this job?
图个退休之后能领那点养老金和一块镀金表
Oh, come on. 30 more years of this, you get a tiny pension and a cheap gold watch.
对
Cool.
- 天呐  这儿真热  - 透不过气
- God, it's hot in here. - There's no air.
- 把门撬开不就行了?  - 憋死了
- Can't they just pry the doors open? - I can't breathe.
别想跟老子较量
Don't fuck with Daddy.
这一下可全完了
Usually they fall down now.
提前了  那杂种提前了
He's early. The son of a bitch is early!
麦克  再派几个人来
Mac, we need more help up here now!
开开门  救救我  我不想死
Oh, please! I don't wanna die!
快开门
Please save us!
快开门  开门
Open the door! Open the door, please!
- 帮帮我  帮帮我  - 我们救你出去
- Please help me! - We'll get you out!
- 快  把手伸过来  没事  - 拉住我
- Give me your hands! It's OK. - Pull me through.
当心头  当心头
Watch your head. Watch your head.
- 出来了  出来了  - 别紧张
- OK, I've got you. - Take it easy.
- 没事了  - 谢谢  谢谢
- You're fine. You're fine. - Thank you.
- 好了  好了  扶一下  - 快  下一个
- Take her. - Who's next?
谢谢
Thank you.
抓住你了
We've got you, ma'am.
- 这是怎么回事?  - 离开这儿  快
- What the hell is all this? - Help us! Hurry!
走  走  快走
Hurry, hurry! Let's go! Go! Go!
快点  快点
Come on. Come on.
我的天
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- 帮帮我  - 当心头  当心
- Help me out! Please, help me out. - Watch your head.
- 过来  快  - 不  不
- Come on, lady! - No.
过来  快过来  拉住我  快
Come on, lady! Come on! Grab my hand!
- 快过来  要坠下去了  - 不
- Come on! Let's go! It's going to fall! - No!
不  我怕
No, I can't!
迈一步  伸出手拉住我
Just take one step, reach out and take my hand.
过来  过来
Come on! Come on!
- 上帝  别抛弃我  - 没事了
- Oh, God! Don't let go of me! - You're OK.
我的鞋子
My shoe!
觉得怎么样?
Was it good for you?
一场虚惊  你说呢  什么滋味儿?
It was great for me. How was it for you, honey?
- 电梯坠落了  - 刺激  太刺激了
- Elevator dropped. - Good. That's good to know.
- 你表慢了?  - 不  不  他提前了
- Is your watch slow? - No. He jumped the gun.
- 提前了三分钟  - 他干嘛呢?
- We had three minutes left. - Why does he do that?
不要这三百万
He's losing his $3 million.
谁知道  也许兴奋得昏了头
Maybe he couldn't hold his wad long enough.
听说这个毛病  上了年纪的人容易犯
It's a common problem among middle-aged men. So I'm told.
他在
He's here.
可能躲在别的地方遥控
He could've blown that thing from Pacoima.
不  他一直监视我们  在附近
No. He knew we were up to something. He's close by.
他疯狂可并不蠢  再说楼里人都疏散了
He's not gonna corner himself in a building we evacuated anyway. Come on.
要不可能在便于转移的地方  对吗?
He'd wanna be here, but he'd wanna stay mobile, right?
在电梯里
The elevators.
客用电梯都锁了  不会在那儿
Passenger cars were stopped. They checked 'em out.
可货用电梯没锁
What about the freight elevators?
- 神秘客人要现身了  - 什么?
- Will the mystery guest please sign in? - What?
杰克
Jack!
妈的
Damn it.
靠边  快靠边
Get to the side!
妈的  妈的  妈的
Shit! Shit! Shit!
起来  给我滚起来
Up! Get your ass up!
恐怕他们是不会为了赎你  给我三百万美金的
I don't suppose anybody'll give me three million just for you.
别动
Hold it!
临时测验  年轻人  恐怖分子浑身绑着炸弹
Pop quiz, hotshot. Terrorist holding a police hostage.
抓了个警察作人质  扬言要炸毁大楼
Got enough dynamite strapped to his chest to blow a building in half.
你怎么办呢?
Now what do you do?
楼底下有五十名警察在等着你呢
There's gonna be 50 cops waiting for you in the basement.
这部署完全符合标准
Standard flanking deployment, right?
我们得靠他们近点  呃?  来个小花招
Maybe we'll get off on the third floor, huh? At least that's what they'll think.
检查一下刚才哪儿在打枪  布里斯  杰克他们呢?
I want location on those goddamn shots! Briggs! Where's Jack and Harry?
警长  货用电梯里梯有情况
Lieutenant, we've got movement on the freight elevator.
停在三楼  快上去
It's on three. Let's move!
说实在的  今天真是太令人失望了
End of the line. This day has been real disappointing, I don't mind saying.
因为你一个人也没杀掉?
Because you didn't kill everyone?
总有那么一天  伙计  你们会后悔见过我
There will come a time, boy, when you'll wish you'd never met me.
我现在已经很后悔了
Mister, I'm already there.
主动权在我的手上  我只要一扔这个  你的朋友就成一堆血浆
I'm in charge here. I drop this stick and they pick your friend up with a sponge.
- 你准备好了吗  伙计?  - 他妈的
- Are you ready to die, friend? - Fuck you.
两百年前有人说  "我后悔把生命献给国家"
In 200 years, we've come from "I regret but I have one life to give for my country"
现在简化成  "他妈的"
to "fuck you"?
- 少说废话  快扔  快扔  - 闭嘴  哈里
- Go ahead. Drop the stick. Do it. - Shut up, Harry.
真是一条不怕死的好汉  伙计
We've got all the balls in the world right here, man.
快投降  你别想跑出去
Give it up. You got nowhere to go!
朝人质开枪啊
Shoot the hostage.
告别吧  哈里
Say goodbye, Harry.
见你的鬼
You fuck!
别动
Freeze!
快投降  你跑不了了
Give it up! You're out of options!
本着无畏和奉献的精神  这两位警察
Through dedication and bravery, these next two officers effected the rescue
拯救了本市十三位公民的生命
of 13 citizens of this city.
由于他们  那凶手葬身于自己设置的炸弹中
And, thanks to them, the only life taken by the terrorist's bomb was his own.
你竟然敢朝我开枪
You shot me. I can't believe it.
还为这个发给你勋章  混蛋
They're giving you a medal for shooting me, you little prick.
哈里  你叫我开的
Harry, you told me to.
奖给洛杉矶警察局的成员
...the Los Angeles Police Department.
警官  哈里·坦波
Officer Harry Temple.
警官  杰克·特莱文
Officer Jack Traven.
好样儿的  杰克  好样儿的
Way to go, Jack. Way to go.
- 拿着  拿着  - 哈里  给
- There we go. - Harry, my man.
好极了  干了它  痛痛快快地喝吧
Beautiful. A toast to me. Make me feel good about myself.
山迪  多喝点
Hey, Sandy! Here we go!
嘿  怎么样?
OK, so how we doing? Whoa, whoa.
给我餐巾
Shit. I need a bib!
- 多喝点  喝吧  - 喝吧  喝吧
- Here we go. All right. - You can't take me anywhere.
这杯  我敬哈里
And here is to Harry,
为他的灵敏
for his quick thinking,
还为他的顾大局  以及他的无私和勇敢
for his grace under pressure and for his brave and selfless act.
对  干  干
Hear! Hear!
另外  为杰克朝哈里开枪
And to Jack, for shooting Harry.
在座各位早就盼着朝他开枪了
Something we've all wanted to do for a very long time.
嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
好了  说正经的
OK, no, no. Here it is.
为了二位尽心尽责  还能死里逃生  干杯
Here's to you guys for doing yourjob and for not getting dead.
干杯
Mazel tov.
我们是天下最幸运的人
We are the two luckiest guys in the world.
那个混蛋给炸死了  电梯里的人都没事
We got the bad guy and we didn't lose any civilians.
- 对  干得好  - 不  是运气好
- We're good. - No. You were lucky.
对  运气好  你心里该清楚
No, we were lucky. You'd better understand it.
那家伙是个狡猾的疯子
We were dealing with a total psycho.
当时我们俩差一点让他给炸死
This guy could've blown us up at any time.
我挨了一枪  不是吗?
And I got a bullet in me.
只差六英寸  就该我老婆上台领奖了
Six inches off the mark, and they're giving the medal to my wife.
哈里  我是说  我们赢了他
Harry, come on, man. I mean, we won. We got him.
你是没听?  还是怎么了?
Do you listen? Do you ever?
要知道  我不能够老跟着你  掩护你  你得多用脑子
Because I am not gonna be around to back you up, so you better start thinking.
不能光凭直觉  否则会送命的
Guts'll get you so far, and then they'll get you killed.
好运不会老跟着你的  对吧  头儿?
Luck runs out sooner or later. Right, Chief?
对
That's right.
没事  没事  我想回家  也想老婆
I'm all right. I'm all right. I'm gonna go home, have some sex.
- 哈里  你到家就会吐  - 那也挺有意思的
- Harry, you're gonna go home and puke. - Yeah, well, that'll be fun, too.
我送送你
Come on, you gimp.
杰克  我看电视了  恭喜你呀
Hey, Jack, saw you on TV. Congratulations.
谢谢  鲍布
Thanks, Bob.
- 你胖了  - 行了  鲍布  别逗他
- You looked fat. - Take it easy on him, Bob.
- 他昨晚一宵没睡  - 狂欢了一宵  呃?
- The boy was up late last night partying. - Wild party, huh?
是啊  闹了一宵
I don't remember that well.
一觉醒来还是光棍
Couldn't have been too great. Woke up alone.
是吗?  记得我有次闹一宵  醒来有了老婆
Yeah? The last time I partied like that, I woke up married, huh, Vinnie?
嗨  杰克  你忘了松糕
Hey, Jack, you forgot your muffins.
- 祝你好运  鲍布  - 谢谢  你多保重
- Have a good one, Bob. - Thanks, Jack. Take care.
谢谢
Thanks.
明儿见
See you tomorrow.
怎么样  杰克?
What do you think, Jack?
你不去把司机的牙捡出来  再得一枚勋章?
You think if you pick up all the bus driver's teeth, they'll give you another medal?
天呐
Jesus!
你当好我对付是吗?
You think I wouldn't have been prepared?
上次电梯的事我准备了整整两年
Two years I spent setting up that elevatorjob.
我把我的一切都投了进去
Two years I invested myself in it.
你想象不出  我耗费了多少心血
You couldn't understand the kind of commitment that I have.
你等于毁了我一生  你以为我会这么轻易地放过你?
You ruined a man's life's work and you think you can walk away?
别做梦了  我引起你的重视了  对吗  杰克?
You got blinders on to the world, but I got your attention now, didn't I, Jack?
- 你干嘛不冲我来呢?  - 为了我自己  为了我的钱
- Why didn't you just come after me? - This is about me. This is about my money.
你们欠我一大笔债  我得讨回来
This is about money due me, which I will collect.
一共是三百七十万美金
$3.7 million.
像我这把年纪的人  杰克  得为将来做打算
It's my nest egg, Jack. At my age, you gotta think ahead.
- 等我把你抓住...  - 临时测验  年轻人
- When I find you... - Pop quiz, hotshot.
一辆巴士有炸弹
There's a bomb on a bus.
当时速超过五十英里的时候  炸弹启动
Once the bus goes 50 miles an hour, the bomb is armed.
再降到五十英里  就会爆炸
If it drops below 50, it blows up.
你怎么办?  你怎么办?
What do you do? What do you do?
- 你说的是哪辆巴士?  - 你认为我会告诉你吗?
- I'd wanna know what bus it was. - You think I'm gonna tell you that?
- 是的  - 这很好
- Yes. - Very good.
有几条游戏规则  杰克  你必须完全照办
There are rules, Jack, and I want you to get this right.
不许乘客离开汽车
No one goes off the bus.
你要是企图让任何人下车  我就会引爆炸弹
You try to take any passengers off the bus, I will detonate it.
在十一点之前把钱给我
I want my money by 11 am.
- 这点时间怕来不及  - 注意听  杰克
- We can't pull that kind of money in time. - Focus, Jack!
你只要管那辆车  车上没有电话  无线电坏了
Your concern is the bus. And don't try to call. The radio's down.
好  那辆车牌号是二五二五  正从洛杉矶西区开往北区
Now, the number of the bus is 2525. It's running downtown from Venice.
在海洋公司和三线交叉
It is at the corner of Ocean Park and Main.
山姆
Sam!
安妮
Annie.
山姆  快停下
Sam! Tell him to stop!
妈的  让我上去
Shit. Excuse me. Coming through! Sam!
- 山姆  - 这又不是车站
- Sam! - This ain't no bus stop.
- 是啊  - 把烟扔了  安妮
- Come on. - Get rid of your butt, Annie.
好  扔了  扔了
OK, it's gone, it's gone.
你是个大好人  将来大家会歌颂你的
You are a good, kind man. One day people are gonna write songs about you.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
- 头一次来这儿  - 不  我住这儿
- First time in LA. - Oh, no. I live here.
我说自己  真是有意思
No, I mean mine. Oh, that's just funny.
- 你听错了  我来游览  - 是吗
- You heard me wrong. I'm sightseeing. - Oh, really?
是啊  我不爱说来"旅游"  可其实是来旅游
Yeah. I hate to use the word "tourist", but it's not like I can hide it.
确实不是
Not really.
天呐  从机场到这儿足足花了三个小时
Aw, jeez. You know, it took me three hours just to get here from the airport.
简直把我脑袋转晕了
I got so lost.
洛杉矶地方可真大  你住在这儿可能没体会
LA is one large place. Course, you live here. You probably don't notice.
我是外乡人  嘿  乡巴佬
I'm such a yokel. There. I said it.
你瞧  我座上粘着这个
You know what? I got gum on my seat.
胶姆糖
Gum.
对不起
Excuse me.
- 早  - 你好
- Morning. - Hi.
我最不愿意车开上高速公路
I just couldn't handle the freeways any more.
太紧张了
I got so tense.
我希望能轻轻松松地去上班
This way, I can just relax all the way to work.
是啊  我的那辆车  就给撞坏了
Yeah, well, I love my car. I miss my car.
上帝  又堵上了
Oh, God. Look at that.
- 山姆  - 妈的
- Hey, Sam! - Shit.
- 山姆  - 什么事?
- Sam! - What?
你干嘛不从空档绕过这些车?
Why don't you just drive over these people?
用不着你指挥  安妮
Don't spit on my bus, Annie.
车真多
Such a mess.
停下
Stop!
- 开开门  开门  - 走开  这儿不是车站不能停
- Open up! - Get off the door. This ain't no bus stop.
- 他也许有什么急事  - 快开门  停车
- That guy really wants to get on the bus. - Open up! Stop!
- 山姆  别让他上来  - 我是警察
- Don't, Sam! Don't let him on! - LAPD!
- 听不见  - 你快停车
- I can't hear you! - Stop this bus!
什么?
What?
我是警察  快停下来
LAPD! Stop the bus!
我是警察
LAPD!
停车
Stop! Stop!
- 我是警察  你快把车给我  - 我说  这辆车是我的
- Stop! LAPD! Get out of the car. - Jesus, not again.
这车是我的  不是偷来的
This is my car. I own this car. It's not stolen.
- 少废话  让开  - 妈的
- It is now. Move over. - Fuck!
我说  你要碰坏了它
Man, you scratch this puppy, and me and you
那我就跟你没个完  懂了吗?
are gonna have words, you understand?
听我说  别开得太快  好吗?  速度稍微放慢一点
OK, look, man, we don't have to go so fast. Just slow down a little bit.
稍微慢点  妈的
Oh, shit. Come on, man.
别碰坏我的车  好吗?
Just don't tear up my car, all right?
你稍微慢一点  行吗?
OK, OK. Just slow down just a bit, all right?
我们有什么必要开得这么快
We don't have to go so fast, do we? We don't have to go so...
你技术可真不赖  伙计
That was a nice move, man.
妈的
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
你慢一点好不好?  慢点
The least you could do is slow down. Come on.
天呐
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
让开  让开  让开  让开
Move! Move!
还是他?
Is that that guy?
看样子他真的很想上这车
Man sure has a hard-on for this bus.
我是警察
Hey! I'm a cop!
什么?
What?
我是警察
I'm a cop!
这是我证件  你车上给人装了炸弹
LAPD! There's a bomb on your bus!
- 什么?  - 你的车上带着炸弹
- What? - There's a bomb on your bus!
车上有...  什么?  妈的
There's a... What? Fuck!
- 你车上带着炸弹  - 当心点  妈的
- There's a bomb on your bus! - Watch the road!
拿着  帮我写一下
Grab that. I want you to write on it.
帮我写一下  "车上有炸弹"
I want you to write on the back: "Bomb on bus. "
快点  快点  快点
Write it, write it, write it!
小心点
Watch the road. Oh, shit.
妈的
Oh, shit!
妈的  不
No!
不能减速
Don't slow down!
不  不  不
No! No, no, no, no, no!
加速
Speed up!
把门打开
Open your door!
Open the doors!
五十  别低于五十英里
50! Stay above 50!
懂吗?
All right?
你来替我拨4708000  要哈里·坦波
4708000. Ask for Detective Harry Temple.
哈里  哈里
Harry.
是杰克
Harry, it's Jack.
我说  你是不是打电话回来想请病假...
You better not be calling in sick, cos I dragged my ass...
- 哈里  他还活着  - 什么?
- Harry, he's alive. - What?
炸电梯的  他回来了
The bomber. He's back.
他已经炸了一辆车  整个车烧得精光
He hit one in Venice already. There's nothing left.
哈里  上次那炸电梯的没死  现在又作案了
We got a ransom demand from your dead terrorist. Says he's rigged a bus.
- 杰克呢?  - 还能在哪儿
- Where's Jack? - Where do you think?
- 我得上那辆巴士  - 你得...
- I gotta get on that bus. - You gotta get...
对  对  你该上那车
Yeah, yeah. You get on the bus.
朝前开
Drive straight!
别摸车道
Stay in this lane!
留神
Watch the road.
等等  你干嘛?
Wait a minute. What are you doin'?
- 买保险了吗?  - 对  干嘛?
- Are you insured? - Yeah! Why?
不  不  啊
No! No!
我的门
You broke my door.
- 先生  借我用下电话  - 尽管用吧
- Sir, I need to take your phone. - Take the phone.
- 你来开  - 什么?
- Take the wheel. - What?
妈的
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
往前开
Drive straight.
妈的
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
妈的
Shit!
这人准疯了
This guy's out of his mind.
别减速  五十英里以上
OK, listen, you gotta stay above 50.
- 对不起  你是疯了吗?  - 别减速
- Excuse me, are you out of your mind? - Whatever it takes.
诸位听着  我是杰克·特莱文警官
Everybody, I'm Jack Traven, LAPD.
现在这辆车上有点情况  小姐  请坐下
We have a slight situation on the bus. If you'll please sit down.
- 不  我不坐  你把大家吓坏了  - 请你坐下
- You're scaring the shit out of these people. - Ma'am, please!
请大家在座位上不要动  保持安静
If everybody will stay in your seats and remain calm,
这个威胁会解除的
we should be able to defuse the problem...
你滚下去
Get away from me!
我不认识你  我不是来抓你的  别这样好吗
I don't know you, man. I'm not here for you. Let's not do this.
- 快停车  - 不能停
- Stop the bus! - He can't.
闭嘴  快停车  停车
Shut up! Stop the bus! Stop it!
喂  喂  听着
Listen!
我把我的枪扔了  好吗?
Look, I'm putting my gun away, OK?
行吗?
OK?
好  听着  不管你曾经犯过什么罪
Now, listen. I don't care about your crime.
我相信你现在已经感到后悔  所以你已经没事了
Whatever you did, I'm sure that you're sorry, so it's cool now. It's over.
我不再是警察了
And I'm not a cop right now.
瞧?  我们两个现在都的普通的...
See? We're just two cool guys, just hanging out...
山姆
Sam!
让我来  我把车稳住  山姆  天呐  山姆
I've got the wheel! I've got it! Sam! Oh God, Sam!
山姆  脚挪开  谁帮我挪开他的脚?
You've gotta move your legs. Can somebody move his legs?
山姆  你把脚挪开
Sam, get your foot off the pedal!
- 我要停车了  - 不  别停  保持五十英里
- I gotta stop this thing! - No! Don't! Stay above 50!
- 可山姆受伤了没法开  - 速度要是慢了  这车会爆炸的
- Sam's been shot! We gotta get him off! - You slow down and this bus'll explode!
这辆车上有炸弹
There is a bomb on this bus.
要是开慢了  会爆炸
If we slow down, it'll blow.
谁要是离开这辆车  也会爆炸
If anyone tries to get off, it'll explode.
胡说  什么炸弹
Bullshit! Yeah, there's a bomb.
- 你开什么玩笑  - 你想惹麻烦?
- Some funny joke, man. - Are we gonna have a problem now?
他还在流血  止都止不住  该怎么办?
He's bleeding so much. I don't know what to do.
紧紧按住他伤口  把他两脚抬高  垫在头底下
Put pressure front and back, keep his legs up and put this under his head.
- 挺住  - 山姆  把头抬一下
- Hold on, man. - Sam, lift your head.
- 小姐  会开巴士吗?  - 我想没问题  就像开大蓬车
- Can you handle this bus? - Sure. It's like driving a really big Pinto.
- 你能不能控制好它?  - 没问题  你有什么主意?
- I need to know! Can you handle it? - I'm fine. Just tell me what the plan is.
- 你有主意吗?  - 暂时先这么开着
- Is there a plan? - For you to drive. We're OK for now.
- 时速别低于五十英里  - 好吧
- Just keep us above 50. - Good plan.
- 你真是个警察?  - 是的
- So, you're a cop, right? - That's right.
可以跟你说实话  我乘巴士是因为执照给吊销了
Well, I should probably tell you that I had my driver's licence revoked.
- 怎么会?  - 超速
- What for? - Speeding.
哈里  我们去现场了  有情况随时联系
Harry, we're on our way to the chopper. If anything changes, let us know.
有关资料全部都在这里
Anything we haven't seen should be in here.
到目前为止  我们知道至少有一辆崭新的美洲虎高级轿车
...wrong with the driver, but at least one car, a Jaguar,
被这辆高速行驶的大客车撞出数米远
has been driven off the road by the speeding bus.
这辆公交客车甚为奇特
The bus came onto the freeway at the Lincoln onramp.
到站均不停靠  车速保持在每小时六十英里左右
It began picking up speed, swerving, and hasn't slowed down since.
一名警官从一辆高速行驶的美洲虎内
Minutes ago a police officer boarded the bus
纵身跳上了这辆巴士
byjumping onto it from a moving car.
准是你  杰克  嘿
Would that be you, Jack?
- 我怎么做?  - 看下各种仪器
- Where do we start? - The speedometer.
有没有损坏  松动  或者有什么  有没有电线?
Has it been fucked with or loosened? See any wires or anything?
对不起  小姐
Excuse me, ma'am.
不  没有
No, it's clean.
那就在车底下  很可能装在车轴上
Then it's gonna be under the bus. Probably rigged to one of the axles.
车底下没法检查  哈里  车正在行驶
I can't get under the bus right now. It's kind of in motion.
对不起
Excuse me! Excuse me!
等一下
Hold on.
车上  有一块...  出入板
Access panel... in the floor.
就在你脚下
Underneath you, man.
哈里  可以了  等我找个乘客
All right, Harry. We're in. Passenger relay.
先生  拿着这个  帮我传一下话
Sir, take this. I want you to tell him what I see.
好的
OK.
好了  我看见了  一个大炸弹
We got a wad! Pretty big!
- 有个大炸弹  - 是黄铜的
- There's a pretty big wad. - Brass fittings!
- 是黄铜的  - 我可以摸到炸弹的电线
- Brass fittings. - I think I can reach the circuit wire.
- 他可以摸到电线  - 不  别动  是圈套  典型的
- He can reach the circuit wire. - No, don't. That's a decoy. Classic.
- 是典型的圈套  - 还有什么?
- Classic decoy. - What else?
- 还有什么?  - 等一下
- What else? - Hold on.
等一下
Hold on.
真妈的
Fuck me!
有了
Oh, darn.
哈里  这玩艺儿  简直能把地球炸了大窟窿
Harry, there's enough C4 on this thing to put a hole in the world.
好吧  好  别慌  沉住气  还有什么?
OK, all right. Just stay calm. What else?
三个启动器  一个在轴上  看不清  一个遥控器
Three triggers -one on the axle I can't really see, a cellular remote
有块手表  可能是定时器
and a timer running off a wristwatch.
- 手表?  什么样的?  - 金的
- A watch? What kind of watch? - Gold.
廉价的镀金手表
Gold band. Fairly cheesy.
警官
Officer!
- 警官  - 你在想什么?
- Officer! - What's on your mind, Harry?
怎么办?  警官
Shit. What do I do? Officer!
- 怎么办  怎么办?  - 妈的
- What do I do? - Oh, shit.
- 走哪儿?  走哪儿?  - 妈的  走边上
- Which way? Which way? - Get on the shoulder.
好的
OK.
留神
Watch it!
下高速公路?  要不要下去?
Stay on or get off? Stay on or get off?
下去  坐稳
Off! Off! Hold on!
上帝
Oh, God.
- 别停  - 红灯
- Keep going. - It's red!
过
Go! Go!
这下好多了
This is much better.
这辆公交大客车  从西区一直高速往南开
...city streets. The bus is on Western, heading in a southbound direction.
目前  沿途的交通秩序  受到严重破坏
Now, where the bus did exit here, it had a couple of close calls.
真是一场精彩球赛
Yeah! Yeah! All right!
不知道当局计划怎么做
We don't know what authorities plan to do.
我不明白
I don't get it.
用手表作计时器  为什么?  什么意思?
The watch is a shitty timer. Why use it? What's he saying?
- 手表几乎人人有  - 他手法不固定
- Lots of people have watches, Harry. - This guy has no MO.
这类案犯一般用惯了哪种炸药  每次作案就都会用它
A bomber falls in love with one kind of bomb and they're very monogamous.
可这人不一样  每次都别出心裁
This guy uses C4, dynamite, different trigger every time,
这次还用了块手表
and now he throws in this watch.
他对所有的炸药性能都了如指掌
He's an encyclopaedia of bombs. He knows every kind.
是啊  还熟悉拆除的方法
Yeah, and everything we do to dismantle it.
等一等
Wait a minute.
我需要看一下前十年的档案
I wanna look at the files for the last 10 years.
- 涉嫌犯的档案全查过了  - 不  要警察的
- We did the mug shots. It's not gonna help. - No. I wanna look at cops.
好吧  我们去
Come on. Let's go.
喂  麦克  你在哪儿?
Yeah. Mac, where have you been?
我要离开公路了  我在市区
I had to bail on the freeway. We're in the city.
我看见你了  你就一直往前开
I can see you. Just keep going straight.
我会想办法为你开路的  跟我保持联系
I'm gonna try to clear the roads for you. Just stay on line.
妈的  我的天  上帝
Shit! Oh, Jesus! God! No!
往左
Go left!
- 对不起  - 上帝
- Sorry. - Oh, my God!
天呐
Oh, jeez!
都给我闪开
People, stay out of my way! Stay out of my way!
- 小姐  往右  - 好  好  好  我知道
- Ma'am, up to the right. - OK, OK, OK. I see it, I see it.
麦克  快带我离开这条路
Mac! Mac, you've gotta get me outta here!
再过几条路口  你就来个小转弯
A few more blocks, you're gonna come up to a soft turn. Right.
往右没有多远  有巡逻车队在等着你
Then hold straight. I've got some units waiting for you there.
他们会把你带到一零五公路  那条路还没有通车  是空的
They're gonna lead you to the 105 freeway. It's not in use. It'll be empty.
- 你就放心在上面开吧  - 知道了
- You'll be totally clear. - Got it.
再过几条马路我们往右拐
In a few blocks, we take the soft turn to the right.
好的  那巡逻车队在什么地方?
OK. Wait a minute. Escort to where? Where do we get an escort to?
小心
Look out!
我的天呐
Oh, God!
你这狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
上帝
Oh, Jesus! Oh, God!
- 我撞着了婴儿  -  罐头
- Oh, God! I just hit the baby! - Cans!
- 不是婴儿  是一车罐头  - 没事?  真的?
- There was no baby. It was full of cans. - Are you sure?
不  不  别过来
Oh, jeez. No! No! No!
- 回学校去  回学校去  - 麦克  车很堵
- Why aren't they at school? - Mac, we're boned.
带你们出去
I'll get you out, Jack.
好  听着  前面有个拐角
All right, listen. You got an entrance coming up, Jack.
你们得拐弯  难度非常大
It's gonna be a real ugly turn, though.
- 有多难?  - 什么难?
- How ugly? - What's ugly?
一会儿我们往右拐  在前面一点
We got a hard right coming up at the construction site.
- 就是这儿  - 这儿没法拐
- This should be it. - That is a dead end.
- 我没这本事  - 你能行  靠左
- I can't make that turn. - You can make it. Keep left. Make it wide.
会翻车的  会翻车的
Oh, God. We're gonna tip over. We're gonna tip over.
会翻车的  大家都到车这边来  快
You're right. We're gonna tip over. Everyone on this side of the bus now!
都到这边来  尽量靠边  快
On this side of the bus! As far as you can, please.
坐稳了
Hold on!
尽量靠边  快  麦克  快把人都散开
Over here. Over here. As far as you can! Now! Mac, you better clear this site out.
- 大家坐稳了  - 往左  尽量往左靠
- Everybody hold on! - This side of the bus!
坐稳了
Hold on!
好  拐了  拐了
Hold on! Oh, God! Here we go! Here we go!
来吧
Here we go!
上帝  好了  都没事吧?
Oh, my God! Oh, God! Is everybody all right?
- 没事了  - 天呐
- Yes! - Oh, my God.
把我送到一零五公路口
Take me to that interchange at the 105.
差点死过去  太可怕了
Oh, my God. We might've died. I can't think.
没事  你要是想吐就吐出来吧
It's OK. If you need to, you go right ahead and vomit.
弗兰克  把那脚手架挪开换成网
Frank, get rid of that scaffolding and replace it with webbing.
把路面的障碍全部清除干净
Norwood, I want aerial units up ahead. No obstructions in the freeway.
我要确保这条公路上畅通无阻
We have a window here. I wanna make sure it stays open.
妈的
Shoot.
你能帮我把一下这个方南盘吗?
Could you do me a favour and hold the wheel for me for a second?
好吗?
Hold the wheel? Thank you.
小姐  干得不错
Ma'am, you did very well.
简直不可思议  没见过这种开法
Actually, you were incredible. I've never seen driving like that.
- 安妮  - 什么?
- Annie. - What?
我的名字叫安妮
It's my name. Annie.
- 安妮  - 别叫我"小姐"
- Annie. - As opposed to "ma'am".
好吧
OK.
我说  这到底是怎么回事?
So, why is all this happening?
我们炸了他的家还是怎么的?
I mean, what did we do? Bomb the guy's country or something?
不  他是为了要钱
No. It's just a guy who wants money.
就为这个  这可不是个好办法
I don't buy that. It's not a very good way to make money.
那么...  你知道这人?
So... what is this guy's deal?
前不久他干过类似的事
A while back, he held some people for ransom.
没让他得手  就想报复我
It went sour, and now he's a little pissed at me.
- 跟我们有什么关系?  - 没有  是游戏
- What does that have to do with us? - Nothing. It's a game.
他拿到钱算他赢  汽车炸了也算他赢
If he gets the money, he wins. If the bus blows up, he wins.
- 你赢了呢?  - 过几天再玩一次
- What if you win? - Tomorrow we'll play another one.
我可不会再来开车玩了  没空
But I'm not available to drive tomorrow. Busy.
所有退休的都查了
We got no match for that description.
没一个警察是缺大姆指的
No one's lost a thumb for at least the last 10 years.
- 可能是外地的  - 这就很难查了
- He could be from anywhere. - I can't access all that.
想起来了  查一下领抚恤金的警察档案
Forget the files. Start going through the pension fund.
这家伙是残疾人  退休以后就住在洛杉机
This guy's drawing disability. He may not be LAPD, but he's living here now.
把照片给我  我见过他
I want pictures! I've seen this asshole.
把乘客从车里弄出来
Hey! Let's get these passengers off the bus!
这绝对不行
We can't do it, sir!
没工夫看你表演特技了
There's no time for any stunts.
得尽快让他们脱离困境
We gotta get these people out of harm's way.
可他不允许  他一直在监视着我们
I got orders. We move these people, he'll see.
你忘了  他是个狡猾的疯子
Remember: crazy, not stupid.
好吧  哈里正在想办法查他  可能是个警察
Harry's trying to find out who this guy is. We think maybe he's a cop.
警长  是他
Lieutenant, it's him.
- 他想找杰克  - 是他打来的
- He wants to talk to Jack. - He's on the line for you.
- 把号码告诉他  - 给他号码
- OK, give him the number. - Give him the number.
- 他怎么样?  - 血不太流了  可...
- How's he doing? - The bleeding is less, but...
- 他们会救我们吗?  - 会的  他们是警察
- Are they going to help us? - Sure they are. They're the police.
靠我们交的税发薪水  当然不希望我们死
Hey, your taxes are paying their salary. If we die, they gotta take a pay cut.
我的意思  是说...
I mean, you know.
是我
Yeah.
我本来很信任你
I think we have trust,
可是从电视上看来  好像你打算让乘客离开巴士
but it looks on TV like you're trying to get those passengers off.
- 有一个必须下车  - 可我们有约在先
- Look, you've gotta let me have one. - We went over the rules.
情况紧急
As an act of faith.
客车司机被人开枪打伤了
We have an injured man here. The driver's been shot.
杰克  是不是你又想朝人质开枪了?
Tell me you haven't been shooting the passengers.
我想警察一般不朝好人开枪  就该朝那些坏人开枪
I thought it was customary for a police officer to shoot the bad guys.
- 这个司机伤势很重  - 我不允许下车
- This man has no time. - No one gets off.
你要发点善心  可以早点拿到赎金
It'll grease the wheels with the money men.
再说还剩不少人质
There's still gonna be plenty of us to kill.
好吧   孩子  你想法让司机下车
OK, son, you can try and unload the driver.
你告诉那开车的野猫  千万别把车的速度放慢
You tell that wildcat behind the wheel not to slow down, though,
否则不等他出去就会炸死  还有  杰克  你别想溜
or he won't even get a chance to bleed to death. And, Jack, don't slip.
- 你说司机可以离开  - 诺沃  再靠近一点
- He's letting us unload the driver. - Norwood! Get us closer!
- 杰克要把司机送到这车上  - 就送他?
- We're gonna get the driver off. - Just him?
- 是的  大个儿  - 奥蒂斯
- For now. Gigantor. - Ortiz.
奥蒂斯  帮一下忙  好的  你把他递给我
Ortiz, we're gonna need your help. I need you to pass him to me.
得小心点别把伤口弄出血了
Keep him straight, or the wound'll tear.
- 让我们也过去  - 嘿  女士
- What about the rest of us? - Hey, hey, hey! Lady!
让我们也过去
I can't stay!
- 怎么样?  - 不过挨了一枪
- How are you feeling? - Like I've been shot.
- 保重  山姆  - 再见
- Take care, Sam. - OK, Annie.
一直开
Drive straight!
- 安妮  尽量靠近他们  - 好的
- Get as close as you can, OK? - All right.
靠近  再近点  安妮
Closer. A little closer, Annie.
- 安妮  再近点  - 好的
- Annie, a little closer. - OK.
行了吗?
OK, how's this?
对不起  对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
安妮  没关系  你再来试一次
OK, Annie. No problem. Let's try it one more time.
再近点
A little more!
好的  好的  就这样  保持距离
OK! OK! Right there! Steady! Hold it steady!
拉住了?  拉住了?
You got him? You got him?
我没事  谢谢
I'm all right. Thanks.
- 上帝  - 太好了
- Oh, my God. - Yes!
他会好起来的
He's gonna be OK.
快  你把手伸给我
Come on! Come on, lady. Give me your hand.
- 我走了  安妮  - 不  海伦
- I have to, Annie. - No, Helen!
- 不  海伦  -  快
- No, Helen, no! - Come on!
海伦  别过去
Helen, no! No!
在未开放的105号公路上
I'm here at the 105 Freeway,
那辆高速行驶的客车由警车护卫着
where the police have successfully led the runaway bus...
不  海伦
No, Helen!
妈的  麦克  赶快把该死的直升飞机调走
Goddamn it, Mac! Get those fucking choppers outta here!
这位勇敢的小姐驾驶着这辆汽车  事态已经越来越难以预料
...was driving the bus. Well, I couldn't tell how old...
刚才发生爆炸  但范围不是很大
An explosion. Some kind of an explosion.
呃  汽车没有爆炸  不过...  我的天
The bus hasn't exploded, but... Oh, my God.
一个人被炸出车外  还被钩在车底下  真是太可怕了
A woman caught in the blast fell. She was pulled under the wheels. This is terrible.
电视的威力  杰克  未来的浪潮  是吧?
Interactive TV, Jack. Wave of the future, huh?
我不该来的
I can't be here.
不该  真的
I can't, you know...
不该上这车
This is the wrong bus.
我不该
I mean, for me to...
不该这么死
I can't die here.
嗨  你闭嘴
Hey, shut up, man.
- 我还有老婆呢  - 是吗?
- I got a wife. - Oh, you do?
嗨  你有老婆怎么了?  我没结婚  难道我就该死吗?
Hey! So if you have a wife and I don't, does that mean I'm expendable?
你这叫什么话呢?
What are you talking about, man?
这人废话太多
The guy's just talking crazy.
听了都心烦  现在谁心里都烦
He gets on my nerves. He gets on everybody's nerves.
- 我认为我有发牢骚的权利  - 你到别的地方去发
- I think I have the right to be a little upset. - What are you staring at, anyway?
你让我们安静点行不行  呃?
Why don't you let us all die in peace, if it has to happen?
就凭你个儿大想欺负人  是不是?
Oh, so you're a really tough guy, huh? Why don't we just step outside?
嘿
Hey!
嗨  你觉得还好吧?
How are you doing? You all right?
别太难过
What can I do?
听了爆炸...
When that bomb went off...
我理解
I know.
我想炸弹  炸弹爆炸了  我死定了
I thought that was it. I thought that was the bomb, and I was dead.
后来看见只有她躺在地上  我就松了一口气...
And then when I saw her body fall under the bus, it was like...
庆幸自己没死
You were glad you were still alive.
- 我太自私了  - 别这么想
- I'm so sorry. - Don't be.
我们都应该庆幸
You should be glad. We all are.
- 这不等于自私  - 那会儿我看见她那么害怕
- It doesn't mean you don't care. - I know, but she was so scared.
她是个好人  不应该死的
She was a nice lady who didn't deserve to get killed,
可安妮  那家伙杀人不眨眼
but if she'd gotten off, it would have killed us all.
他是个恶棍  安妮  会有报应的  记住这个  呃?
He's the asshole, Annie. The guy who put us here. Remember that, OK?
是恶魔
Big asshole.
好的
OK.
肯定吗?
Are you sure?
有多宽?
Well, how far?
警长  呃  有个严重的情况
Sir, we have a serious problem.
什么?
What?
- 这条公路还没竣工  - 什么? 你说什么?
- This freeway isn't finished. - What are you talking about?
空中巡逻队发现  前面三英里左右的地方有断切面
The aerial unit caught it. About three miles ahead there's a section missing.
断切面?
A section missing?
可这地图上并没注明有什么断切面
But it's on the map. It's finished on the goddamn map!
可能没有按时完工
I guess they fell behind.
妈的  混蛋  都是一帮混蛋
Fuck! You're fired. Everybody's fucking fired!
靠过来一点
Get me closer!
嘿  靠近点  从镜子里看
Hey, get closer. Watch him in the mirror.
杰克
Jack!
- 断面有多宽?  - 至少有... 五十英尺
- How big is the section? - 50 feet... at least.
前头路面有个豁口  很宽
There's a gap in the road up ahead. It's big.
- 开玩笑  多宽?  - 五十英尺
- You're kidding. How big? - 50 feet.
什么?
What?
看来只能把乘客弄下车
We gotta get these people off the bus somehow.
这行不通
You know I can't.
他说什么?
What did he say? Jack?
Jack, what did he say?
什么事?  怎么了?
What's the matter?
- 前面有个大豁口  - 什么?
- There's a gap in the freeway. - What?
- 怎么回事?  - 多大的口子?
- What do you mean? - How big is a gap?
五十英尺
50 feet. A couple of miles ahead.
真要人命了
This is crazy.
- 天呐  - 杰克
- Jeez. - Jack.
拉到空挡让马达空转行不行?
Jack. What if I shift into neutral and just keep the engine revving?
- 不  行不通  - 怎么办? 说呀  说呀
- No, he'd have thought of that. - What, then? What? What?
妈的  说呀  杰克
What? Jack?
- 加速  - 什么?
- Floor it. - What?
那是交叉口  可能有坡度  加速
Floor it. It's an interchange. There might be an incline.
好吧
Fine.
请大家坐稳  抓住前面的靠背拉手
Everybody hold onto your seats or whatever you can.
到了豁口  低下头
When we hit the gap, heads down.
就这样?  就这样?
That's it? That's it?
只能这样了  把这些放到座位底下
That's all we can do. Let's put these underneath your seat, all right?
把包都放到座位底下
Put your bags underneath the seat.
- 我不是有意开枪的  - 坐稳了
- Hey, I didn't mean to shoot the guy. - Hold on.
你能有把握吗?
Is this really gonna work?
杰克
Jack.
来了
Yeah?
杰克
Jack.
- 加速  加速  加速  - 上帝
- Come on, come on, come one. - Oh, God.
- 加速  -  天呐
- Come on! - Oh, God.
真要命
Oh, shit.
大家坐稳了
Everybody hold on!
上帝  杰克
Oh, God. Jack.
天呐
Shit!
不可思议
Yes! We are way out of control!
- 没事吧?  - 没事
- You OK? - Yeah.
- 还好吗?  - 我很好
- You OK? - I'm OK.
好的  诺沃  我们走
All right! Norwood, let's go!
- 大家没事吧  - 没事  哈
- Is everybody OK? - Yes!
成功了
We did it!
We made it.
你真是好样儿的
You're the man. You are the man!
谢谢  谢谢大家
Thank you. Thank you very much.
天呐
Oh, shit.
- 你真是个天才  - 什么天才?
- I think you missed your calling. - Yeah? What was it?
小心点  你该当飞行员
Watch the road. You should have been a pilot.
- 下去  - 什么?
- Get off. - What?
从这儿开出去  快点
Get off this. Now. Get off this.
[ 洛 杉 矶 机 场 入 口 ]
往这儿
In there.
- 什么?  这儿?  - 对
- Where? Right here? - Yeah.
- 是这儿吗?  - 没错
- Right here? - Yeah.
- 他开进机场了  - 飞机场?  那儿的人可不少
- He's just entered the airport. - There's thousands of people there.
好样的  杰克  在里面兜圈  这主意不错
That's my boy Jack. He can circle the runways and buy us some time.
- 电视台的直升飞机进不去  - 他往停机坪去了
- Choppers can't fly there. It's restricted. - He's headed for the end of the field.
- 停机坪那头有一条应急跑道  - 但愿修好了  我们走
- Bravo Tango, an emergency runway. - Let's hope it's built. Let's move!
这儿是机场
We're at the airport.
是啊  怎么?
Yeah? So?
我看着像机场
I already seen the airport.
- 喂  - 非常  非常  激动人心
- Yeah? - Very, very exciting, Jack.
杰克  差点没命  呃?  可是你表现得非常出色
Some close calls, huh? But you've done all right for yourself.
- 什么事?  - 我要那笔钱
- What do you want? - I want money, Jack.
也许  呃  我有比这更崇高的目标  不过恐怕到头来只能为了钱
I wish I had some loftier purpose, but I'm afraid in the end it's just the money, Jack.
你叫他们把不连号码的纸币  装在两只塑料口袋里  别作记号
I would like large non-sequential bills in two clear plastic bags, unmarked.
- 听明白了吗?  - 你干嘛跟我说?
- Can you remember all that? - What are you telling me for?
我要你帮我拿到那笔钱  避免悲剧
Because I want you to help me to get it before it gets too late.
我不喜欢谈判  杰克  那些人嘴上说得好听
I hate negotiators, Jack. They talk to you like they're your best friend
背地里总想着办法来治你
and they don't even know you.
你说他们干嘛要耍我  呃?  他们当我拿人命开玩笑?
Why are they messing with me, huh? Do they think I'm doing this for fun?
- 你不是吗?  - 别这样  杰克
- Aren't you? - Oh, that's unfair, Jack.
你根本不知道我的感受  你不了解我
You don't know how I feel about this. You don't even know me.
你想发财可不想付代价
You want a shitload of money you didn't earn.
我付了
Oh, I earned it.
我付了我一生作代价
I spent my life earning it.
我也得过奖  可是得奖的同时  也得到了一份解雇通知单
I got a medal, too, Jack, a medal and a pink slip and a "sorry about your hand".
- 你得让我出去  - 不
- You have to let me off. - Oh, no.
- 这可办不到  - 你要我帮你?
- That's not good. - You want me to help you?
我就得找他们当面谈  因为他们不相信你
I need to talk to these people face to face. They think you're bullshit.
那就让他们等着瞧
They don't think that.
你要钱  我要保护这些人的性命
Look, you want the money, I don't want anyone else to die.
你放我出去
Let me get on the ground.
就放我  这不违反规则
Just me. That's not against the rules.
好吧  可是不能耽搁太久
All right. I want you back real fast.
行
Fine.
杰克  不许耍花招  我比你高明得多
Jack, nothing tricky now. You know that I'm on top of you.
你无论如何也斗不过我
Do not attempt to grow a brain.
- 你跟他谈妥了吗?  - 妥了
- So I guess there's a plan now? - Could be.
- 怎么?  - 他放我下车
- Yeah? - He's letting me off.
- 什么?  - 你还接着开  没事
- What? - Just keep circling. You'll be fine.
- 大家多保重  我去去就来  - 那你还会回来吗?
- Sit tight. I'm getting off for a minute. - Do you think that's a good idea?
- 我会回来的  - 你不管我们了吗?
- It'll be OK. - Are you just gonna leave us here?
- 还用问?  - 放心  我就回来
- I would. - Don't worry. I won't go far.
嗨  别忘了我们
Hey. Don't forget about us.
电视台的飞机走了  可以救人了
The choppers are gone. Let's dump the passengers.
- 不行  他会知道  - 他打哪儿知道?
- He's ready for that. - How is that possible?
我也不清楚  可我能肯定  每次他总能抢先一步
I don't know how. I just know he is. He's been a step ahead every time.
- 他会先动手引爆炸弹的  - 你说该怎么办?
- If we unload, he'll take them out. - So where does that put us?
试试看  把炸弹拆除
I have to try and dismantle that bomb.
这辆公交车经历了十号公路
After an incredible ride on the 10 freeway,
和一零五公路的险情之后
the streets of Los Angeles and the 105 freeway,
接着开进了洛杉矶的国际机场  绕着一条应急跑道继续行驶
this bus has ended up here at Los Angeles International Airport, circling the runway.
我说  安妮  他准不会回来了
I'm telling you, he's somewhere jerking off.
别忘了当时他是主动要上车的
He didn't have to get on the bus in the first place, Ortiz.
嗨  别过这根黄线
Get your ass behind the yellow line.
他干嘛?
What is that?
这我也不知道
I have no idea.
这根绳支持不了几分钟
We won't be able to hold this steady for long.
我也只能有几分钟时间  试试看也许来得及
I just need a few minutes. If I can't do it by then, I can't do it at all.
- 哈里  帮我  - 好  当心点  杰克
- Harry, you with me? - Yeah. You be careful, Jack.
他干嘛?  上帝  他真疯了
What's he doing? Oh, my God. He is insane.
好了  杰克  开始吧  别丢了命
OK, Jack, this is it. Don't get dead.
- 这不是好主意  - 他准能行
- This is not a very good plan. - Have faith, sister.
老天爷
Oh, Christ.
你得把车开稳一点
Just keep it steady.
谢谢提醒  奥蒂斯
Thank you for the tip, Ortiz.
他简直疯了
This guy is nuts!
那个装置上有电池  你暂时别去碰它
We'll try to bypass the remote current with the battery.
- 你有没有看见引爆线?  - 不知道  这儿有几根电线
- Can you find the tripwire for the remote? - I don't know. I got a few choices here.
- 黑和红?  - 还有绿
- Black and red? - And green.
恐怕他不会用铜丝做引爆线
OK, I'm gonna guess he's not gonna go with standard copper for the remote.
电流量太小  他会用合金纤维
That'd be too weak. I'd use a fibre alloy.
杰克  找找那根合金电线
Jack, I'm gonna need you to look at the wire.
都给包住了
Harry, it's covered.
知道  你把外包皮切开  不能切断那电线
I know. You're gonna have to cut off the sheath. But don't cut the wire.
好
Right.
妈的
Fuck me!
Shit!
- 找到了  - 太棒了
- Bull's-eye! - Great.
你先把电池夹住然后绕过引爆器
OK. I want you to clip on the battery and then run it to the lead wire.
明白
Copy.
绕不过去  会引爆的
I can't bypass. It'll fire.
妈的  他有防备了
Oh, shit! It's a collapsible circuit.
霍沃·派恩  警察局拆弹组成员  一九八九年在执行任务时
Howard Payne, Atlanta PD Bomb Squad. Retired in Sun Valley in 1989
被炸断了一根姆指  受伤后不久退休
when a small charge left him with fingers numbering nine.
就这狗娘养的  找着他了  杰克
That's our scumbag! We got him. Jack, we found him.
他住处离这儿不远
We can get to his place inside of 15 minutes.
好  杰克  你不用拆了
Jack, get out of there.
- 我们这就去捣他的老窝  - 你要小心
- We're going after the source. - Watch your back.
等等  等等我
Wait for me!
麦克  拉我出去
Mac, get me outta here.
谁去后面看看他出来没有  快
Somebody go to the back and check and see if he came out the back. Go!
- 看见他了吗?  - 后面看不见他
- Can you see him? - He's not behind us.
- 什么?  - 没看见他人
- What? - He's not back here.
上帝  上帝  再去看看
Oh, my God. Go look!
再看看车底下  看看他是不是在车底下
Lay down and look under the bus and see if you can see him down there.
- 看见了吗?  - 没有
- Can you see him? - No.
你再仔细看看  车胎后面有没有?
You don't see him back by the tyre or something?
- 也没有  - 肯定吗?
- I can't see him. - Are you sure?
没看见他
I can't see him.
撞着他了  上帝  看见他了吗?
Oh, my God! We hit him! Oh, my God! Do you see him?
- 撞着他了?  - 到两边窗口看看他在不在
- Did we hit him? - Look out the sides.
- 工具  - 快点给他工具
- My tools! - Will somebody get him his tools?
动作快一点
Please help him! Hurry!
他准在车底下  看见了吗?
God, we're dragging him. Do you see him?
他在吗?  在吗?
Where is he? Is he there?
- 他在吗?  - 杰克
- Do you see him? - Jack! Jack!
- 看见他了  - 什么?
- I see him! - What?
- 看见他了  - 他没事吧?
- I see him! - You do? Is he OK?
他没事  他没事
He's all right! He's all right!
拉住我  拉住我  快拉住我的腿
Hold my legs. Hold my legs. Somebody hold my legs.
拉住他  拉住他
Hold his legs.
- 拉住腿  - 加油
- Hold his legs! - Come on!
来呀  来  行了
Come on! I got ya!
- 他好吗?  没受伤吧?  - 上来  上来
- Is he hurt? Is he OK? - Pull! Pull!
来  来
Come on! Come on!
上来了  来  上来
We got him now. Come on, pull!
真是个奇迹
Jesus. I can't believe it.
你真是一个疯子  杰克  知道吗?  谢天谢地
You are a complete jerk. You know that?
- 你去拆炸弹了?  - 是的  差点爆炸
- Did you have any luck with the bomb? - Yeah. It didn't go off.
奥蒂斯  谢谢
Ortiz, thanks.
你的命真大  伙计
How many lives you got, man?
你可真是条好汉  凭这股劲你可以多找几个姑娘
You're not too bright, man, but you got some big, round, hairy cojones.
你是叫...  叫什么  奥蒂斯
That's... very gross, Ortiz.
我是想夸夸你
Can't even pay him a compliment.
- 怎么样?  - 你吓死了我  杰克
- How you doing? - You scared the shit out of me, Jack!
不过我没事
Other than that, I'm fine.
- 什么味儿?  - 汽油
- What is that smell? - It's gas.
- 这车漏油了?  - 怪哉
- We're leaking gas? - We are now.
你是不是想再历一次险?
You felt you needed another challenge or something?
- 麦克  - 杰克  什么事?
- Mac. - Mac here. Go ahead.
你能不能找辆油车  这车漏油了
Can you get a fuel truck to pace us? We're losing gas.
- 这就去找  能坚持多久?  - 十分钟左右吧  情况不妙
- I'll see what I can find. How much time? -10 minutes? It doesn't look good.
好吧  诺沃  你现在赶紧去找一辆油车
Gotcha. Norwood, get a fuel car out here on the double.
能坚持吗?
Is that gonna work?
不知道
I don't know.
快呀  快救救我
Harry, save my life.
哈里  你有什么好消息?
Harry, tell me good news, man.
抱歉  杰克  他失败了
Oh, I'm sorry, Jack. He didn't make it.
混蛋
You fuck!
是那块手表把他引到我家去的  呃?
It was the watch that led him to me, wasn't it? Huh?
用我那珍贵的退休礼物制作炸弹
It seemed a little hammy to me to build
是不是太富有戏剧性了?
the bomb out of my precious retirement gift,
可这实际上是在暗示他  "霍沃派恩在等着他"
but, you know, I figured a sign that said "Howard Payne" would be pushing it.
我向上帝发誓  非把你撕成碎片不可
I'm gonna rip your fucking spine out, I swear to God.
可你还是得照我说的去做
You're gonna do exactly as you're told.
杰克  我知道哈里生前是你的搭档  是你的智囊
Jack, we both know that he was the brains of your particular operation.
你们斗不过我  就得给我那笔线
You can't beat me. You're gonna pay me every dollar.
要不然  你和那个野猫  还有车上那些个无辜的乘客
Otherwise, you, the wildcat and every innocent person on that bus
会跟你朋友同样下场
are gonna end up just like your friend.
听清楚了吗?  听见我说的了?
Are you paying attention? Jack, are you listening to me?
- 杰克  杰克  - 在
- Jack? Jack? - Yeah.
很好  靠百胜广场的东北角
Good. You tell them that the drop point is Pershing Square.
有一个垃圾桶
There's a garbage can on the northeast corner.
叫他们把钱扔在那桶里
You drop the bags and leave.
我等他们离开以后  会去把那钱袋取出来的
I don't show until all your people are gone.
已经快到十一点了  我预感到今天会是个最最愉快的日子
It's getting on to 11 am, Jack, and I think it's gonna be a very pretty day.
杰克
Jack.
好了  杰克  别这样  杰克  你别泄气
Come on. Don't give up on me, Jack! Jack, stop it! Jack, come on!
别这样  好吗?  你千万不能泄气
Stop it, OK? Don't give up on me right now, all right?
我心里真害怕  大家都需要你  我一个人对付不了这局面
We're really scared and we need you right now. I can't do this by myself. Please?
杰克  求你了
Jack, please.
好吗?  求你了  好吗?
OK? Please. All right?
- 我们会死的  - 不会的  你别泄气  好吗?
- We're gonna die. - No, we're not. We got this far, OK?
真该死
I'll be damned.
你上过阿历桑那州立大学?
Did you go to the University ofArizona?
- 是啊  怎么了?  - 球队很棒
- Yeah? So? - Good football team.
也许吧  谁知道呢
Yeah, I guess so. I don't really know.
阿历桑那野猫球队
Arizona Wildcats.
- 怎么?  - 他看得见
- Right. - He can see you.
- 什么?  - 他看得见你
- What? - He can see you.
你只管朝前面看
Just keep looking straight ahead.
他一直称你"野猫"  这杂种在你头顶上安了摄像机
He called you a wildcat before. Bastard's got a camera right in your face.
我当傻子当到现在
He can see the whole bus. He's been playing me from minute one.
- 那么  他看得见也听得见?  - 听不见  只看得见
- Well, he can see me, but can he hear me? - Doesn't look like it. He's just watching.
据本台记者报道  这辆高速行驶的公交汽车
We are following the progress of what is turning out to be a harrowing story,
车上装有炸弹   一旦减速会引起爆炸
as a city bus, rigged to explode if it slows down,
它一直在沿着飞机场的跑道兜圈子
races around literally in circles at the Los Angeles airport.
有一名女乘客和另一辆巴士的司机
The dead are a female passenger and a driver of another bus,
都已被车上的炸弹炸死
both blown up by the bomber.
这个恐怖事件的发生
Others in jeopardy are the passengers of the bus,
据说是出于一个疯子的变态心理
held hostage at the whim of a madman.
我有变态心理
"The whim of a madman. "
说得好
I like that.
在我的左肩上方有一台摄像机
There's a camera on the bus just over my left shoulder.
现在要求大家朝前看
I want you to stare straight ahead.
坐在位置上不要动  好吗?
Don't make any big movements, OK?
我是杰克
It's Jack.
是的  我知道了
Yeah, I know about Harry.
电视台的车在吗?
Is that news van still around?
- 叫记者暂停播放  - 好的
- Get those cameras to stop taping. - Right.
我是警察  借一下机器   能播放超高频吗?
LAPD. I need this unit. You can broadcast UHF, right?
请帮我找出那车上的频道
There's a signal going to that bus. I want you to find it.
请大家现在暂时停一下
We're gonna have to take you off the air.
有紧急情况  只好请大家暂时停下
Please, sir, stop taping.
快点  快点  好  录下来
Come on, hurry up. Good! Tape off of that.
别做大动作  显得累点
Remember, no big movements. Just look whipped.
这个倒不难做到
That ain't gonna be too hard.
- 录下来  快  录下来  - 我录了
- Tape it. Good. Come on, tape it. - It's taping!
- 杰克  - 啊
- Jack. - Yeah?
看
Look.
- 麦克  汽油  - 杰克  等五分钟
- Mac, fuel. - Jack, five minutes.
没时间了  放录像  转移人吧
Not enough time. Run the tape. We have to unload.
- 可我才录了一分钟  - 快放
- I only have a minute of tape. - Do it now.
把刚才录好的  做一盘循环带反覆播放
I want you to make a tape and loop it so that it runs over and over, OK?
- 好了  放  快放  - 好吧  开始播放了
- All right, run it. Run it! - All right. Tape's rolling.
还没收到新的实况录像  据记者报道  汽车仍在继续沿机场跑道兜圈子
We still have no live picture, but reports are that the bus continues to circle...
车上乘客暂时没有新的伤亡
Everyone is safe for the moment.
此时此刻  这些乘客在想些什么
Hard to imagine what's going through their thoughts at this time.
不过可以肯定他们每一个人...
Certainly, a sense of community...
稳住方向盘  踩住油门
Rig the steering wheel and the gas pedal.
好了  开始吧  一个个过
All right, let's get 'em off.
好  你  你  你
OK, you, you, and you.
警方发布了一个情况报告
Police have just issued a general statement,
内容跟以前差不多
which doesn't tell us much more...
抓住手  对了  好
Grab my wrist. That's it. Good.
过来  别往下看
Come on. Look straight ahead.
-  很好  - 抓住我的手腕
- That's good, that's good. - Grab my wrist.
伸出手  抓住他的手
Put your hand out. Take his hand.
过来  伙计  别害怕
Come on, buddy. I got ya.
把手给我  快点
Give me your hand. Your hand.
抓住我  别低头
Grab my hand. Don't look down.
妈的
Shit!
杰克
Jack!
抓紧我
Grab my hand! Grab my hand!
杰克  我稳不住它了
Jack! Jack, I can't hold this any more.
安妮
Annie!
安妮  坚持住
You... hold on!
不  不  不
No! No! No!
坚持住
Hold it.
- 上帝  - 用这抵住油门
- Oh, God. - Wedge down the gas pedal.
好  好  抵住了
OK, I got it.
- 系好了?  - 对  系好了
- You got it? - Yeah. I got it.
- 安妮  下去  - 我不行  杰克  我不行
- OK, Annie, get on. - Jack, I can't do this.
- 快点  快点  - 妈的  妈的
- Let's go! Let's go! - Shit. Shit.
- 呃  杰克  - 妈的  快点
- Jack. - Shit!
好  好
Hold on.
妈的
Shit!
你好吗?
Are you all right?
还行
No.
没事  都过去了
It's OK. It's OK. It's over.
安妮  你成功了
It's over. You did it. You did it.
再也不来机场了
I hate the airport.
你会对我有感情吗?
You're not gonna get mushy on me, are you?
也许  没准
Maybe. I might.
在紧张的情况下产生的感情不会牢靠
I hope not, cos relationships that start under intense circumstances never last.
- 是吗?  - 我研究过这个问题
- Oh, yeah? - I've done extensive studying on this.
救兵来了
Here comes the cavalry.
- 怎么样  - 没事
- How ya doing? - We're OK.
我做一次好人  放你半天假
I just might be a nice guy and let you have the rest of the day off.
太好了
Oh, boy.
麦克  这是安妮
Mac, this is Annie.
安妮  这是麦克蒙警长
Annie, meet Lieutenant McMahon.
- 你好  - 你好
- How you doing? - OK.
这伤口得消消毒
This should take care of it.
- 哟  轻点  - 对不起
- Watch it. - Sorry.
- 送你们去医院治一下  - 警长
- We're gonna have you guys checked out. - Lieutenant!
是他  问我们几时把钱送去
It's him. He wants to know when he's gonna get his money.
狗娘养的  现在只有上帝能帮助我们了
I'll tell him what to do with his goddamn money.
嗨  他并不知道我们已经离开巴士了
He doesn't know it blew up.
30分钟后行动
30 minutes.
呆在这里  千万别离开
I'll be right back.
好  现在开始行动  你  你  去一号位置
All right, here's our target. Fox, I want you in 4-1, you in 1-2. You're in 3. Let's move it.
- 其他人跟我走  打开跟踪器了吗?  - 已经打开了  长官
- Is the paint bomb in with the money? - It's done, sir.
杰克  你成不了好警察
Too bad, Jack. You could've made a good cop.
好
OK.
还没收到新的实况录像  据记者报道  汽车仍在继续沿机场跑道兜圈子
We still have no live picture. Reports are that the bus continues to circle inside LAX.
不  不
No! No!
小姐  你不能待在这里  不安全
Miss, you can't be this close. You need to move back.
不  杰克·特莱文说...
No. Jack Traven said...
杰克·特来文警官要我带你去一个安全的场所  快跟我走吧
Jack Traven asked that you be brought out of harm's way. Just move right over here.
- 看来他迟到了  - 不可能
- He's running a little late. - He's not late.
- 什么?  - 他不会迟到
- What? - He's never late.
可那钱还在那儿
Well, that money hasn't moved.
上百双眼睛盯那只桶  钱里还有跟踪器  他插翅难逃
We got 200 eyes on that can, a bird dog in the bag. I'd say he's covered.
- 打开  - 为什么?  他还没...
- Turn it on. - What for? It hasn't moved.
打开
Just do it.
妈的  在动  钱拿走了
Shit. It's moving. He's got the money.
杰克
Jack!
妈的
Shit!
不许动
Freeze!
临时测验  混蛋  枪口对着你的脑门
Pop quiz, asshole. You have a hair trigger aimed at your head.
你怎么办?  你怎么办?
What do you do? What do you do?
转过来  转过来
Turn around. Turn around!
- 不  - 对不起
- Oh, no. - I'm sorry.
准备测验
Be prepared.
童子军面临人生的考验
It's the Boy Scout marching song.
你怎么办  杰克?  我想你不会朝她开枪吧?
What are you gonna do, Jack? I don't think you can shoot her.
放她走
Let her go.
不  这恐怕办不到
No, I don't think I'm gonna do that.
装上  快
Fill it. Now.
哈里要是知道又重头开始了
I think Harry would be very disappointed,
恐怕会感到非常失望的  呃?
feeling that we're right back where we started.
放她走  干嘛还绑她?  你拿着钱走吧  走吧
Let her go. You don't need her. You have the money. Take it and walk.
你拿着钱快走吧  你不需要她
Come on. Just take it and walk. You don't need her.
- 拿着你的臭钱赶紧走开  - 别过来  你别过来
- Just take your goddamn money and walk! - Stay right there.
我会引爆的  我会的
I'll do it. I'll let go. I'll let go.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我看你至今还没明白过来  呃?
You still don't get it, do you, Jack? Huh? The beauty of it.
造炸弹是为了让它爆炸  这是它的意义和作用
A bomb is made to explode. That's its meaning, its purpose.
你在瞎忙乎因为你想不让它爆炸  不让它发挥它的威力
Your life is empty because you spend it trying to stop the bomb from becoming.
你图的是什么?
And for who? For what?
要知道  不炸的炸弹算什么玩意儿?
Do you know what a bomb is, Jack, that doesn't explode?
不过是一堆廉价的镀金手表  伙计
It is a cheap gold watch, buddy.
你是疯子  是该死的疯子
You're crazy. You're fucking crazy.
不  穷人才是疯子  杰克
No. Poor people are crazy, Jack.
我只是癖好  拿着钱
I'm eccentric. Get the money. Let's go.
走吧  走啊  快走啊
Come on! Let's go! Move it! Move it!
你呆着  快走啊  快走啊
You stay! Move it! Move it!
快进去  快进去  快
In the door. In that door! Now!
再见  杰克  蠢货
Bye, Jack. Punk.
闪开
All right!
上车  快上车
Get in there. Go on, get in.
你给我进去  马上开车  快
You get back in there! You get this train moving! Go on!
你们占着座?
Are these seats taken?
不  走
No. Go.
快  给我过来  把手伸过来
Come on. Back over here. Hands around the pole.
开呀
Damn.
开呀  开呀
Come on, come on, come on!
往西方向的五零一次  现在在哪儿?
Please report, Westbound 501. What is your position?
往西方向的五零一次  请回电话
Westbound 501, please check in.
五零一次  我们接到警方命令  你马上开回站  听见了吗?  请回话
Westbound 501. We have police orders to return to the station. Do you copy?
你拿着  捏着这个把  帮个忙
You have to hold this. It's like a grenade. You have to help me now. Come on, hold it.
好  捏好了  别松手  呃?  靠你了
Don't let it go. Huh? I'm counting on you.
听见了吗?  请回话
Do you copy?
嘿  我来接替你
Hey! I'll take it from here.
看来还得让我来拿着
Maybe you'd better let me have this after all.
我看你实在太紧张了
I'm afraid you're a bit hysterical.
会提早把这玩意儿引爆了
and you might let this go a mite early.
嘿  嘿  听我说
Hey! Hey, buckaroo!
过会儿你再帮我拿  好吗?
It's not cos you're a woman, all right?
嘿  没事  你得跟我配合
Hey, it's all right. Looks like we're all alone.
你赢了  赢了杰克  赢了大家
You won. You beat Jack. You beat everybody.
把我扔出去吧  我不在乎
Just throw me off the train. I don't care.
这个  呃  是个遥控器
This stick works on a remote.
等你一爆炸  他们会过来  可不会找到我
When you explode, that's where they'll come, but it's not where I'll be.
我另有个计划  你粉身碎骨  他们一下会认不出
I have a different plan. Mess like that, they don't even count body parts.
你再忍一下
Gives me more time.
那样死没有痛苦  安妮
It's not gonna hurt, Annie.
嘿  杰克  是你吗?
Hey, Jack, is that you?
这小子可真有股子韧劲
He's so persistent. He always gets his man.
我给你钱  你别再缠着我了  好吗?
Wouldn't be able to interest you in a bribe, would I?
我有好多好多的钱
I've got plenty to go around.
我的钱
My money!
你这狗杂种  我叫你耍我
You bastard! How does that feel?
叫你耍我  狗杂种
You like that, huh? You like it, you bastard?
我的钱
My money!
妈的
Shit!
你  我饶不了你  杰克
You! I'm coming for you, Jack!
嘿  遥控器在这儿  想要吗?
Hey, I'll drop the stick, boy. You want that?
呃  我饶不了你
I'm gonna get you.
太爽了
Oh, yes!
还有招吗  杰克  呃?  你自以为很聪明  是吗?
What do you do, Jack? What do you do? You're so smart, right, Jack?
小杂种  你斗不过我  因为我比你高明
You piece of shit! I'm the guy with the plan cos I'm smarter than you.
比你高出一百倍
I'm smarter than you.
是啊
Yeah.
可我比你高
But I'm taller.
杰克  杰克
Jack.
快来救我
Jack!
天呐  我以为你死了  杰克
Oh, God! I thought you were dead. Jack.
- 转过去  - 他呢?
- Turn around. - Where's Payne?
脑袋掉了
He lost his head.
天呐
Oh, God.
- 把这卸了  好吗?  - 好  把它卸了
- Let's take this off, shall we? - Yes. Let's take this off.
- 卸了它  - 喂  喂
- Take it off. - Hello? Hello?
请回话  杰克  我是麦克  听见了吗?
Does anyone copy? Jack, this is Mac. Can you hear me?
杰克  你在吗?  快把车停下  那轨道没完工
Jack, if you're there, you've got to stop the train. The track isn't finished.
麦克  知道了
Mac, I copy.
- 麦克  - 谁能听到吗?
- Mac. - If someone can hear me...
- 麦克  听见了吗?  - 拉紧急刹车  杰克  请回话
- Mac, can you hear me? - Try the emergency brake. Do you copy?
全坏了  安妮  这下糟糕了
Nothing works! Annie, you won't believe this.
什么?
What?
我们得跳车
We have to jump.
刹不住
You can't stop it?
那么  把我手铐打开
Well, OK, undo me, and I'd love to go with you. Come on.
- 我没钥匙  - 什么?
- I don't have a key. - What?
我没钥匙
I don't have the key.
妈的
Shit.
你快跳车  你快离开这辆列车
You gotta get off... You gotta get off the train.
杰克  快走  这个轨道是死的
Jack, please! This track dead-ends. You gotta get off this train. This is crazy.
有个拐口
There's a curve ahead.
我把速度加大  让车冲出去
I'm gonna speed it up, make it jump the track.
你别犯傻了  你跳车吧
This is really stupid. Jack, please. You can still jump.
杰克  杰克  求你
Jack, please. Please, Jack?
它竟横着撞过来  没事  我的天
I can't believe he hit my van. Come on. It's all right.
真不敢相信
Unreal.
你居然没走
You didn't leave me.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
你留下了
You didn't leave me.
没有别的选择
Didn't have anywhere to be just then.
看看
Check it out.
我要提醒你
I have to warn you.
我听说紧张的情况下产生的感情是不会牢靠的
I've heard relationships based on intense experiences never work.
好吧
OK.
我们用爱来巩固它
We'll have to base it on sex, then.
听你的  小姐
Whatever you say, ma'am.